supanet.com 2018-08-19

# PRIVACY POLICY

PRIVACY POLICY                                                                   (i.e customer and/or technical support). We may ask you for certain
                                                                                 information to confirm your identity, check our records and to enable us
                                                                                 to deal with your enquiry quickly and efficiently. Calls to our support
Here at supanet we treat your privacy and the security of your data very         lines may be recorded for quality and training purposes.
seriously. We are open and transparent as to the circumstances in which       • sign up for any of our newsletters or mailing lists or to receive service
we collect data from you and more importantly what we do with your data          notifications from us so that we can send you what you wish to receive.
once collected.                                                                  The information we collect may include your name, address, telephone
What is the aim of this policy?                                                  number and contact email address.
The aim of this policy is to explain clearly and simply:                      We automatically collect information from you when:
• When, how and what information we collect from or about you and why         • you use the services we provide to you. This includes the IP address of
• How we use the information we collect and what we won’t do with it             the router and the MAC address of the device you use to connect to
• The ways in which you can access and manage your information,                  your router to access your broadband services, the amount of time you
   including how you can request copies of your data                             spend online, the websites you visit, the amount of bandwidth you use
• How we keep your data secure                                                   and, in the case of our telephone services, the number you call, the time
                                                                                 of your call, its duration, its destination and how the call is routed. We
From time to time we may make changes to this policy (for example to             collect this data, either ourselves or via our wholesale providers, for
keep pace with best practices or changes in legislation) so we suggest that      billing purposes, to manage our network and to comply with our legal
you check back every now and again so that you make sure you are happy           obligations.
with any changes. For our customers, we will notify as and when changes
are made.                                                                     • visit our website we may collect and process information about how and
                                                                                 when you visit and use our site. We do this using ‘cookies’ and other
Should you have any questions or queries about this policy we would be           similar technologies. We explain this in more detail below and in our
happy to assist. Please direct your queries to dataprotection@supanet.net        Cookie Policy, which is available on our website. We do this to help us
                                                                                 improve our website and the user experience.
What is the scope of this policy?
                                                                              We also collect information about you from other sources (i.e third parties)
This policy applies to anyone who visits our website and/or to anyone who
                                                                              when:
uses any of the services we provide. By subscribing to or using our
services, or by visiting our website, you’re agreeing to this policy and,     • you place an order for our services we will, with your permission,
importantly, to us using your information in the ways described in this          undertake a credit check with a credit reference agency. In doing so we
policy.                                                                          will receive personal information about you, in particular in relation to
                                                                                 your credit history. We use this information to determine whether and on
You should read this policy in conjunction with our terms and conditions
                                                                                 what terms to enter into a contract with you and to prevent fraud. There
(both for the use of our website and the services we provide) as well as, in
                                                                                 is a specific section below providing more information about credit
the case of our customers, any other terms we may provide you with that
                                                                                 checks.
relate to our services
                                                                              • provisioning our services we may also receive information from other
What information do we collect?
                                                                                 telecommunications providers which is required to enable us to provide
General                                                                          services to you .
We collect information about you when you contact us to enquire about our     How we use your information?
services and when you subscribe to and use our services. As well as
                                                                              We collect information to better understand our customers and those
collecting information from you we will also collect information from other
                                                                              interested in our services and to deliver the best possible service. We
organisations, such as credit agencies, as well as from organisations we
                                                                              respect your data as being yours and will only process is when there is a
need to involve or use to provide services to you, for example BT
                                                                              lawful purpose or need for doing so.
Openreach or wholesale telecommunication providers. In addition to
receiving information from other organisations we may also share your         Examples of how me may use your data (the information we collect from
information with other organisations so that we can provide the services      and about you) are:
you order from us and so that we can manage and maintain those
services, as well as administer your account with us.                         • dealing with enquiries about our services and processing orders you
                                                                                 place with us for services. We may use systems that make automated
What information do we collect, when and how do we collect it, from where        decisions about the products and services we are able to offer you, the
do we collect it and why?                                                        terms upon which we are able to contract with you and which wholesale
                                                                                 providers we use to provide you with services
We collect information directly from you when:
                                                                              • verifying your identity when you contact us or when you use our
• you enquire about or place an order for our products and services. We
                                                                                 services
   ask you to provide certain information need from you so that we can
   determine the availability and suitability of our services, explain and    • providing personalised, efficient and co-ordinated customer service,
   discuss services that are available and answer any questions you may          technical support and complaints handling. We may monitor, record,
   have. Calls to our sales lines and enquiries made via ‘live chat’ or other    make notes of and store telephone, email, electronic and other
   electronic means may be recorded for quality and training purposes.           communications we may have with you concerning both your services
   This information may include your name, address, the proposed service         and your account with us. We do this for quality assurance and training
   address (if it is different from your current address) your telephone and     purposes, to make sure that we have an accurate record of your
   email contact details as well as information about your current               instructions and to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
   telecommunications services (if any) and your future
   telecommunications requirements. If you place an order with us we will     • notifying you of changes to our services, prices or the terms upon which
   also need to collect additional information from you to enable us to          the services are made available to you;
   identify you, process your order, enter into a contract with you and       • investigating, reporting, logging and resolving any faults or issues in
   provide you with services. This information may include your date of          relation to the services
   birth, any previous residential address if you have lived at your current
   address for less than 3 years and your bank and/or credit card details.    • notifying you of any matters affecting our network and/or your use of the
   We may also need to ask you for other information depending on the            services including any restrictions that may have been placed on your
   nature of your order (for example if you are moving to the service            account/service;
   address, your move date).
                                                                              • calculating and invoicing you for charges incurred using our services,
• contact us to discuss your active services or administer your account

   processing and collecting payment or charges, communicating with you         Whenever we share your information we will only disclose information to
   in relation to billing, payment and credit control matters, including taking the extent it is necessary and, as far as is reasonably possible, that
   steps to recover any monies you may owe us                                   arrangements are in place to ensure that your information is kept secure,
                                                                                in accordance with applicable data protection legislation and is only used
• investigating and resolving any complaints you may make about our             for the purpose for which it is disclosed to them.
   services;
                                                                                There may be occasions when third parties to whom we disclose
• sending you communications which you have requested and that may              information are outside the European Economic Area in countries whose
   be of interest to you                                                        laws may not afford the same level of protection of data as those in the
• investigating, preventing or detecting criminal activity, fraud or misuse     European Economic Area or the United Kingdom. Should these occasions
   of, or damage to our network and enforcing our acceptable use policy         arise, we will ensure that your information is not shared until a contract is
                                                                                in place to make sure your information is adequately protected and that
• monitoring traffic over our network and other systems for planning,           appropriate measures are in place with the aim of ensuring that your
   problem solving and security reasons                                         privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this policy.
We may also use your information for other lawful purposes. In some             Credit Checks
instances we may seek your express and informed consent, where this is
required. In other, very limited circumstances, we may use your information     When processing your order for products and services we may carry out a
where we have a legitimate reason for doing so or in where we are               credit check. We will ask you before doing so. A credit check involves us
required to use your data to comply with legal and/or regulatory obligations    checking:
that are imposed upon us.                                                       • Our own records
When do we share your information with others?                                  • The records maintained by a credit reference agency. We will share
We will NOT:                                                                       certain information you have provided us with (normally your name, date
                                                                                   of birth and address) when submitting our search request together with
• sell or rent your personal information to third parties                          details of the nature of the services you are ordering. Our search will
• share your information with third parties for marketing purposes                 place a search ‘footprint’ on your credit file that may be seen by other
• share your information other than in accordance with this privacy                organisations. We receive information that is both public (including
   policy without first obtaining your consent                                     information on the electoral register) and shared credit and fraud
                                                                                   prevention information. If you tell us about a spouse or financial
We may:
                                                                                   associate, we may link your records together. Credit reference agencies
• pass your information to third parties we engage for the purpose of              may also link your records together, and these searches will be
   carrying out certain tasks or functions relating to the provision of            recorded on linked credit files.
   services to you and administering your account with us (for example
                                                                                • records maintained by fraud prevention agencies
   undertaking credit checks or setting up and processing direct debit or
   card payments or outsourcing customer support). The payments you
   make to us may be processed by third party payment processors, who
   specialise in the secure capture and processing of credit/debit card         How long to we keep your information?
   transactions and direct debit collections. If you wish to find our more,     The amount of time we retain your personal information is subject to
   please contact us. When undertaking credit checks and/or processing          regular review and will vary according to the reason for which the
   payments we may receive information about you from those third party         information is used. We are legally required to hold some types of
   providers. We will hold this information in accordance with this Privacy     information to fulfil our statutory or regulatory obligations (for example we
   Policy.                                                                      are required by OFCOM to retain recordings of sales calls for not less than
• disclose or transfer your information to a third party in anticipation of or  6 months and we are legally required to retain certain information about
   as part of a sale of some or all of our business to any third party or as    how you use of our services for a period of 12 months so that it may be
   part of any business restructuring or reorganisation                         made available, subject to a lawful request being made, to law
                                                                                enforcement agencies for the purposes of preventing and detecting crime
• disclose your personal information if we are under a duty to disclose or      and protecting national security).
   share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, if
   we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the    Your personal information will be retained on our systems for as long as is
   purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime or to enforce or apply our    reasonably necessary for the relevant activity, or for as long as you are our
   terms of use or to protect the rights, property or safety of our users and   customer (or until our performance of the contract is complete) and for a
   customers.                                                                   reasonable period of time thereafter.
• share your information for the purposes of any current or future legal        We will hold information about you if you enquire about services but do not
   proceedings or any alternative dispute resolution process. For example,      become a customer. We may also continue to hold information after you
   should you refer any complaint to our alternative dispute resolution         have closed your account or terminated your services with us. We will only
   provider for determination, we may share with that provider information      hold such information for such periods as is necessary for the purpose of
   we have which is relevant to the complaint.                                  dealing with enquiries, offering you our products and services you may be
                                                                                interested in, complying with any legal obligation and for crime and fraud
• share your information with debt recovery organisations or legal              prevention and detection.
   advisors for the purposes of recovering monies that you may owe us
                                                                                What choices do you have in relation to marketing communications?
• provide your information to law enforcement agencies in response to
   properly made requests relating to the prevention and detection of a         When you have given your consent for us to do so, we may contact you
   crime, for the purpose of safeguarding national security or when the law     with details of products, services and special offers that we believe you
   requires us to                                                               may be interested in. Should you decide that you no longer wish to receive
                                                                                marketing communications from us, just contact us you can contact us,
• providing information in circumstances where we are required to               either by:
   respond to properly made requests from regulatory bodies, including the
   Information Commissioners Office and Ofcom.                                  • sending an email to marketing@supanet.net
• providing information to banks, building societies or credit card             • calling us on 01282 777711
   companies regarding transactions relating to your account, including but
   not limited to responding to charge back claims or claims made under
   the Direct Debit guarantee

and we will update your preferences and stop sending you marketing              We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If
communications. However, we will continue to send you communications            you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian's permission
about any services you have with us, for example notifications about any        beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.
changes to your services or our terms and conditions.
                                                                                CONTACT US
Can you access and update your information?
                                                                                If you feel we have breached your privacy, want us to update your
Yes. The accuracy of your information is really important to us. If your        marketing preferences or amend your information, please contact us
contact or payment details change or any of the other information we hold       either:
becomes inaccurate or out of date, please email us at: cs@supanet.net or
call us on 01282 777711 and we will happily update your information.            By letter:
You have a legal right to request us to provide you with a copy of the          Data Protection – TCS Contact Centre, Time Technology Park, Blackburn
information we hold about you without charge. Before complying with your        Road, Simonstone, Lancashire BB12 7TW
request we may have to ask you to provide or confirm information for the        By email:
purposes of verifying your identity and for you to provide us with
information so that we can comply with your request (for example, your          dataprotection@supanet.net
account number, telephone number, address, post code and, if you are
                                                                                OUR COMPANY INFORMATION
requesting a call recording, the date and time of the call and the telephone
number from or to the call was made.                                            supanet is a trading name of Supatel Limited, a company incorporated in
                                                                                Cyrus with company registration number 267725 whose registered office
If you wish to request copies of your personal information please:
                                                                                address is at:
• Write to us at: Data Request, TCS Contact Centre,
                                                                                STADYL Building,
    Time Technology Park, Blackburn Road, Simonstone,
                                                                                Corner Them.
    Lancashire BB12 7TW; or
                                                                                Dervis-Florinis Street,
• Email us at: datarequest@supanet.net                                          CY-1065 Nicosia,
                                                                                Cyprus
• Call us on 01282 777711
Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration
of your information
We take steps to ensure that your information it’s treated securely. Any
sensitive information (such as credit or debit card details) is encrypted and
protected with the following software 128 Bit encryption on SSL. When you
are on a secure page, a lock icon will appear on the bottom of web
browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer.
Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted normally
over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As
a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot
guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so
at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best
effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or
where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain
parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password
confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.
Use of 'cookies'
Like many other websites, our website uses cookies. 'Cookies' are small
pieces of information sent by an organisation to your computer and stored
on your hard drive to allow that website to recognise you when you visit.
They collect statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns and
do not identify you as an individual. For example, we use cookies to store
your country preference. This helps us to improve our website and deliver
a better more personalised service.
It is possible to switch off cookies by setting your browser preferences. For
more information on how to switch off cookies on your computer, visit our
full cookies policy. Turning cookies of may result in a loss of functionality
when using our website.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites run by other
organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we
encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you
visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of
other sites even if you access them using links from our website.
In addition, if you linked to our website from a third party site, we cannot be
responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and
operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy
of that third party site.
16 or Under
